Finding aid to the Margaret Mahoney papers SSC.MS.00230
Sophia Smith Collection
- Photographs, 1925-2007; 5; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  The second sub-series, Scrapbook photographs, ranges from 1940-2007. The photographs were culled from two scrapbooks collected by Margaret. Due to the acidic condition of these scrapbooks, and additionally because photographs were increasingly becoming dislodged from their place in the scrapbook, the photos were removed from their original location. Upon removal, it was difficult to determine the original location of photographs, however the photographs retain their original labels, if any, given by Margaret. In the instance that that it was unclear which labels referred to which photographs, the page was photocopied and placed in with the photographs.
  The Professional photographs sub-series document events and places from Margaret's professional life, including her UNESCO travels to Mexico and Lebanon in 1947.
  The Other photographs sub-series contains photographs encountered in the collection, generally housed in envelopes. Quotation marks around the folder title indicate the original label applied by Margaret. These photographs document her childhood, her social life at Vanderbilt, and her travels, among other miscellaneous topics.
  - Portraits of Margaret Mahoney, approximately 1940-1960 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - MEM photo.tif, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Portraits of Margaret Mahoney, 1965-1990; 3.5 inch floppy disk (Box 52, Folder 1-6)
  - Scrapbook photographs, Honorary degrees and awards, 1977-1983 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook photographs, Margaret Mahoney with one other person, 1983-1995 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook photographs, Margaret Mahoney and others, 1951-1997 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook photographs, Identified others, 1940-1984 (Box 52, Folder 10-14)
  - Scrapbook photographs, Unidentified people, 1960-2007 (Box 52, Folder 15-16)
  - Scrapbook photographs, UNESCO, 1950-1951 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Professional photos, Carnegie good-bye to Margaret Mahoney, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Professional photos, Harkness House, 1980-2005 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Professional photos, conferences and events, 1950-1982 (Box 52, Folder 20-21)
  - Professional photos, conferences and events, 1982-1998 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Professional photos, UNESCO, Trip to Mexico City, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Professional photos, UNESCO, Lebanon, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Other photos, "Childhood", approximately 1925-1955 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Other photos, Christmas cards with photographs, 1964-1999 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Other photos, Delta Delta Delta Fraternity, 1 Feb 1943 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Other photos, Egypt tour scrapbook, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 8-12)
  - Other photos, Kodak pictures taken by Margaret Mahoney in Washington, D.C.; New York; Woods Hole; Monteagle; W.-Blemont, approximately 1924-1970 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Other photos, "London Paris", approximately 1924-2012 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Other photos, Maine trip, Carol Richards, 1995-1996 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Other photos, Margaret Mahoney with Nell Savage Mahoney and McNeills at Foulkeways, 1983-1986 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Other photos, Miscellaneous events, 1994-2001 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Other photos, Monteagle, 1925 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Other photos, Social events, 1953-1973 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Other photos, Trinity Church, 1988-1995 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Other photos, "Washington,", 1952-1954 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Other photos, Wedding of Elizabeth Zerfoss to Syd Houston Hailey, July 1942 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Vivienne Brown-Jerry, 28 Dec 1998; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - MEM portraits in Harkness House, 1997-2002; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Anne and John Summerfield, approximately 1924-2012; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Roz Whitehead, Margaret Mahoney, and Carol Richards in Maine, Aug 1994; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified portraits, approximately 1924-2012; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1935-2006; 6; 5.5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This series consists of two sub-series: Unpublished and Published.
  Unpublished materials comprise a very small portion of the series and comprise mostly Margaret's diaries from 1935-2003.
  The Published sub-series consists of speeches, reports, and articles written by Margaret from 1947-2006. This sub-series is arranged chronologically. In several cases, Margaret delivered a speech and subsequently revised it into a published article. In those instances, all related materials have been placed together and are arranged by the earliest iteration of the speech/article.
  This series provides a good understanding of Margaret's opinions on the contemporary state of philanthropy, healthcare, mentorship, and civic engagement. It includes her research and revisions for the President's Reports in the Commonwealth Fund annual report from 1982-1994. Of particular interest to scholars of gender and labor is Margaret's speech "Part Time for a Lifetime," delivered at Wellesley in 1981 and subsequently revised and published in Working Woman in 1983.
  - Diaries, 1935-2003 (Box 54, Folder 1-10)
  - Essay topics, 1991-1994 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - "College Programs in the Arts for Non-Arts Majors,", approximately 1953 (Box 54, Folder 12-13)
  - "Report on Mountain-Plains Regional Conference on UNESCO," U.S. National Commission for UNESCO, 28 Jul 1947 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - "International Theatre Month: March 1950," Theatre Arts, Mar 1951 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous unpublished fiction, approximately 1957-1972 (Box 54, Folder 16-17)
  - "Momentum for Change," American Journal of Nursing, Nov 1969 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - The Arts on Campus, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - "The Arts in Education," Planning Corporation for the Arts, Apr 1971 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - "The Opportunities and Constraints for the University in the Arts," Southeastern College Art Conference, 26 Apr 1972 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - "The Spectrum of the Health Professions: Evaluation and Testing Issues," National Board of Medical Examiners, 15 May 1972 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - "The Future Role of Physician Assistants and Nurse Practitioners in the USA,", 19-22 Jun 1972 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Art book drafts, correspondence, illustrations, research, 1972-1973 (Box 55, Folder 8-15)
  - "The Role of the Medical Student in the University Complex," George Washington University, 5 Feb 1973 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - "The Changing Health Care System," Hospital and Health Planning Council of Metropolitan New Jersey, 26 Apr 1973 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - "Toward an Evaluation System for Health Education," the Pharos, Apr 1973 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - "A Greater Struggle: Society's Changing Response to Changing Health Needs," Beth Israel Hospital Social Work Department 45th Anniversary Celebration, 11 May 1973 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - "Foundation material,", 09 Oct 1973 (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - "The Dollar Impact on New Directions in Medical Education and Practice" speech and publication, 1973-1974 (Box 55, Folder 21-22)
  - Foundation Subcommittee on Health, Smithers Foundation, 30 Jan 1974 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "A Review of 'The Rise of the Arts on the American Campus'" Foundation News, Jan-Feb 1974 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - "The American Hospital of the Future," New England Association for Hospital Development, 1 Apr 1974 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - "The Arts in the Education Process," New York University, 7 Mar 1974 (Box 56, Folder 4-5)
  - Princeton High School Talk speech and reference material, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 6-7)
  - "The American Foundation and Other Institutions" speech and publication, 1974-1975 (Box 56, Folder 8-9)
  - "The Crisis of Ignorance," The Maine Medical Center, 21 Nov 1974 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - "The Subtleties in Reaching Out: The Colleges, the Communities and the Arts," Arts in Society, 1972-1975 (Box 56, Folder 11-14)
  - Analysis of Three Year Funding, Robert Wood Johnson Foundation board meeting, Mar 1975 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - "Preparing the Family-Oriented Physician for Practice in the United States," International Conference on the Family Doctor, 22-25 Apr 1975 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - "A General Principle: Evaluation as a Planning Tool for Foundations," Council on Foundations, 14 May 1976 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "How Does a Child Become an Adult?" General staff presentation, 13 July 1976 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Buck Hill Falls presentation, 29 July 1976 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - "Learning through participation in the arts," Christian Science Monitor, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 4, Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Panel talk on "Manpower Requirements in the Changing Health Care Scene," New Jersey Society of Internal Medicine, 10 Nov 1976 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Iowa Public Radio Interview, Iowa State University: Arts in Education Series, 18 Nov 1976 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - "As a Planning Tool: Evaluation Can Help Make the Manager's Life Easier," Foundation News, Nov/Dec 1976 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - "A Programmed Development of a New Foundation," Clearinghouse for Midcontinent Foundations, final text, staff edits, and news clippings, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 8-9)
  - "One Perspective on the Importance of Ambulatory Services," Annual Meeting of the Assembly of Ambulatory and Home Care Services, 19 Sep 1977 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Convocation Ceremony, Meharry Medical College, 03 Oct 1977 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - "The Critical Cues in Society for Medical Education: or God sent a message to Earth asking its inhabitants to vacate by noon, because he had other tenants," Humanities Intensive Conference, 29 Oct 1977 (Box 57, Folder 12-13)
  - Preface to John Russell's Giving and Taking: Across the Foundation Desk, 1976-1977 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - "Careers in Health Administration: An Interpretation of Needs along Three Professional Paths," Northwestern University, 17 May 1978 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - "Dilemmas for the Young Woman Executive," Columbia University final copy, correspondence, and drafts, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 16-17)
  - "Endowed Cats Catch No Mice," staff luncheon presentation, 14 Mar 1978 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - "Mission: To Contribute to the Health and Well-Being of Every Citizen," San Francisco, 16 Oct 1978 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - "Notes on Child Abuse,", 19 June 1979 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - A Tribute in Memory of Charles Frankel, Kennedy Center, 16 Aug 1979 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - "A Perspective on Child Care Needs in the 1980s," Institute of Medicine, speech, correspondence, publication, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 22-23)
  - "A Perspective on Child Care Needs in the 1980s," Institute of Medicine, speech, correspondence, publication, 1979 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - "Children's Health Care Needs Lack Broad-Based Constituency," Hospital Progress, June 1980 (Box 58, Folder 2-4)
  - "Attitudes Affecting Child Health Care: A Perspective on the 1980s," Advances in Pediatrics, 1982 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Mary E Switzer Memorial lecture: "Allied Health Professions: Planning for the Future" speech, publication, correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 6-8)
  - "One Outlook on American Institutions in the 1980s," New Jersey Society of Fund Raising Executives, drafts, final speech (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
  - "Child Care in the 1980s" Yale University, 02 Apr 1980 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - "The 1980s: What's Ahead for Children?" United Hospital Fund of New York, 30 Apr 1980 (Box 58, Folder 12-13)
  - "Remarks on Carleton Chapman," The Commonwealth Fund Board of Trustees, 08 May 1980 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Mt. Sinai Talk and interview, 1 Nov 1980- 25 Feb 1981 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - "Clinical Scholars and the Future of Urban Medical Care," Annual Meeting of the Clinical Scholars, 15 Nov 1980 (Box 58, Folder 16-17)
  - "Healthcare in the 1980s: Does It Still Need Philanthropy?" Grantmakers in Health Conference, 18 Nov 1980 (Box 58, Folder 18-19)
  - "A Reception for Paul and Joan Marks," Columbia University, 02 Dec 1980 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Remarks, Commonwealth Fund Forum, 12 Aug 1981 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Comments on David Hamburg, Institute of Medicine, 15 Sep 1981 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - "Stability in Motion," The National Conference on Philanthropy, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 23-25)
  - "Part Time for a Lifetime," Wellesley College, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 1-5)
  - "For Women: A Lifetime of Work," Women and Foundations/Corporate Philanthropy, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - "Preparing for the Future," Working Woman, Nov 1983 (Box 59, Folder 7-8)
  - Mount Sinai speech, manuscripts, related materials, staff comments and edits, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 9-11)
  - "Medical Care and Medical Research in New Zealand and Australia,", 14 Jan 1982 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - "The Foundation Connection," Foundation News, Jan-Feb 1982 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - "A Personal Review of the Fund's First 30 Months and Plans for the Future,", 15 Feb 1982 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - "Interesting Times," Foulkeways, 08 Mar 1982 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Founder's Day Honors Convocation, The Medical College of Pennsylvania, 27 Mar 1982 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Presentation, Conference of Southwest Foundations, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, staff comments and edits, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 17-22)
  - "What New Yorkers Think about their Health Care," Annual Report of Commonwealth Fund, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "A Talk," Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, related materials, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 2-7)
  - "Strengthening Community Leadership in the 80s," The Central Exchange, drafts, correspondence, final manuscript, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 8-9)
  - Testimony to Congress, 27-30 June 1983 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - "Mentors," Commonwealth Fund president's report, correspondence, drafts, final copy, notes, references, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 11-17)
  - "Overview of the Present," Commonwealth Fund, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - "Variations in the Use of Medical Services: The Need for Knowledge," California Academy of Medicine, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, references, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 19-21)
  - "Variations in the Use of Medical Services: The Need for Knowledge," California Academy of Medicine, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, references, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
  - "Creative Leadership," University of Rochester, correspondence, speech, references, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
  - "Creating Opportunities for People to Live in Good Health," Associated Grantmakers of Massachusetts, 08 June 1984 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - "Introduction," Schools and Museums, 11 July 1984 (Box 61, Folder 7-8)
  - "What's Ahead for Children?" Monteagle Sunday School Assembly correspondence, final speech, related material, 1983-1984 (Box 61, Folder 9-12)
  - Ethics submission, Foundation News, July/August 1984 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Greeting, Harkness Fellows meeting manuscript, reference materials, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 14-15)
  - Keynote Address, John Hopkins University School of Nursing, correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 61, Folder 16-17)
  - Introduction of Cal Plimpton and Roy Atherton, The River Club, 12 Nov 1984 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - "Leadership," Commonwealth Fund Annual Report, correspondence, final publication, mailing, references, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 19-23)
  - "Leadership," Commonwealth Fund Annual Report, correspondence, final publication, mailing, references, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
  - "Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse," Grantmakers in Health and the New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 06 Feb 1985 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Private Philanthropy and Public Policy, American Enterprise Institute, 20 Mar 1985 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Opening comments, Council on Foundations, 24 Apr 1985 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Richard Berman Award, National Conference of Christians and Jews, 15 May 1985 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Remarks, The Living-at-Home Program Advisory Committee Meeting, 20 June 1985 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - "The Future of Nursing Education in the University," SUNY-Albany, correspondence, reference, manuscript, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 8-9)
  - "The Future of Us All: Growing Old in America," Geriatric Resources Corporation dinner, correspondence, references, manuscripts, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 10-12)
  - "Heroes," Commonwealth Fund annual report, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, references, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 13-19)
  - "Heroes," Commonwealth Fund annual report, correspondence, drafts, final manuscript, references, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1-3)
  - "America's Elderly Population: A Public Health Story," Cosmopolitan Club luncheon, correspondence, references, drafts, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 4-5)
  - "A Prescription for Change: Government and Corporate Influences on Patient/Physician Relations," New York Academy of Medicine, correspondence, references, drafts, final manuscript, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 6-8)
  - Introduction of Peter Hannaford, Council on Foundations luncheon, 15 Apr 1986 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - "Heroes in Our Time," Donors Forum, correspondence, reference material, drafts, final manuscript, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 10-13)
  - "Seeking Medical Advice to Determine Appropriate Care," Business and Health, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Review of Alan Pifer book, The Pharos, Fall 1986 (Box 63, Folder 15-17)
  - "Families" annual report, Commonwealth Fund, correspondence, drafts 1-10, final version, spanish version, reference material, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 18-21)
  - "Families" annual report, Commonwealth Fund, correspondence, drafts 1-10, final version, spanish version, reference material, 1986 (Box 64, Folder 1-6)
  - Introduction of Thornton F. Bradshaw, Council on Foundations, 01 Apr 1987 (Box 64, Folder 7-8)
  - "Health," Report of the Commission on the Year 2000, June 1987 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Introduction to "Harkness House" pamphlet, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - "Partners" annual report, Commonwealth Fund correspondence, drafts, final, references, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 11-20)
  - "Partners" annual report, Commonwealth Fund correspondence, drafts, final, references, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Book review, New England Journal of Medicine, July 1988 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - "Doers" annual report, Commonwealth Fund, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - "What the Future of Philanthropy Holds," Philanthropy, Jan-Feb 1989 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - "Inspirers" annual report, Commonwealth Fund drafts and references, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 6-10)
  - "Medical Rights and the Public Welfare," American Philosophical Society, 21 Apr 1990, drafts, notes, references (Box 65, Folder 11-16)
  - Events, The American Philosophical Society, "Claude Anne Lopez" and "Symposium on Human Rights,", 1990 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Mary Mount College references and notes, 20 May 1990 (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Mount Sinai convocation speech references, 18 Sep 1990 (Box 65, Folder 18-21)
  - "Bring Back Public Health!" op-ed, 20 Sep 1990 (Box 65, Folder 22, Box 66, Folder 1-3)
  - "A Community's Role and Responsibility in the Modern World," Donors Forum of Ohio, 25 Oct 1990, drafts, references (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
  - "Mentors," One Plus One, conference, correspondence, and drafts, 1989-1990 (Box 66, Folder 6-8)
  - "Communicators" annual report, Commonwealth Fund, drafts, notes, final, references, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 9-16)
  - New York Historical Society references, 27 Mar 1991 (Box 66, Folder 17-19)
  - William Plowden notes, 17 June 1991 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - "Healing Broken Communities: Building for the Future," American Philosophical Society, 13 Nov 1992 (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Paul Bruce Dowling eulogy, 30 June 1994 (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - "Innovators," The Philanthropic Initiative, summer 1994 (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - "Make Known What You Know," Foundation News and Commentary, Mar/Apr 1995 (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Op-ed Material, 1994-1995 (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Robert Higgins Ebert obituary, The Century Association Yearbook, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Remarks, Medical University of South Carolina, 01 Apr 1997 (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - "What Do You Do? Give Away Money? The True Value of Organized Philanthropy," Conference of Southwest Foundations, 09 Oct 1998 (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - "Philanthropic Management," Conference on Raising the Value of Philanthropy, 22 May 2000 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Remarks, Robert Wood Johnson Foundation dinner to honor Ruby Hearn, 30 Apr 2001 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Remarks, Paul Beeson Physician Faculty Scholars in Aging, 17 June 2001 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Children's Fund of Connecticut and Child Health and Development Institute of Connecticut, 07 Dec 2001 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Remarks, John W. Gardner Memorial, 17 Apr 2002 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Remarks, Philanthropy Northwest Early Childhood Learning Affinity Group, 17 May 2002 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Seattle Talks on Healthy Steps, 17 May 2002 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Memorial Service for Nathan J. Stark, 25 Nov 2002 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Eulogy for Eli Ginzberg, 18 Dec 2002 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Remarks, National Committee for Quality Assurance award dinner for Harvey Picker, 25 Mar 2003 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - "Partnerships," Funder's Network, 21 May 2003 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Remarks, Memorial Service for Kurt W. Deuschle, 22 May 2003 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Speech, Watkins College of Art and Design, 13 May 2004 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Remarks, Commonwealth Fund Board of Directors dinner honoring Lawrence S. Huntington, 8 Nov 2004 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Remarks, Waldemar Nielson Memorial, 2 Dec 2005 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Alan Pifer memorial, 9 Jan 2006 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Tribute in Honor of Jeremiah Barondess, 17 Oct 2006 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Commonwealth Fund President's Report, 1982-1994 (Box 67, Folder 18-19)
  - Introductions to Commonwealth Fund Papers, 1982-1987 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - "Perspectives on Health Fund Raising:" American Hospital of the Future, 1 Apr 1974; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Joint Staff meeting on Child Abuse, 19 Jun 1979; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - First annual meeting, "General Pediatrics Academic Development Program", 13-14 Sep 1979; DC-60 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - "Tim Ireland talk" backup tape, 9 Feb 1988; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - "Women's Health in the 90s", 16 Mar 1994; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - World Foundations State dinner, 18 Apr 1994; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - "Innovators" and 10/23 dictation, 1994; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - "5/2", approximately 1924-2012; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - "Fd News 2", approximately 1924-2012; 1/8 in. audiocassette (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - "To Margaret Mahoney from CFPC," Community Family Planning Council, approximately 1924-2012; T-10 VHS (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - "Society's Changing Response to Changing Health Needs," Colloquium at Beth Israel Hospital, 11 May 1973 (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Donors Forum newsletter, 7 May 1986 (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
- Subject files, 1961-2007; 7; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. The section on People complements Series 2. Correspondence. That section includes information about Rene Maheu, the 6th Director-General of UNESCO, who Margaret met through her work supporting UNESCO. Maheu was a classmate and close friend of Simone de Beauvoir and Jean-Paul Sartre. The file on Tennessee history includes photographs.
  Of particular interest are the Allan Kaprow "Happenings" posters.
  - Aging old people, 1986-1987 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Art, 1970-1972 (Box 67, Folder 22-24)
  - Art/Education, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Economy, 1986-1987 (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Education, 1986-1987 (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Employment, 1986-1987 (Box 67, Folder 28)
  - Patient cases, 1968-1974 (Box 67, Folder 29)